Guide to the Loomis-Wilder Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- MARY WILDER LOOMIS (1833-1910), 1855-1910; Series III; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. See the general note on correspondence in the Introduction to the register. The few personal papers of M.W. Loomis may be found in Series II, together with biographical materials about some of those who corresponded with Mr. and Mrs. Loomis. Cross-references have been made on the appropriate folders.
  - Correspondence
    - A (6), Circa1860's-1907 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Ammindon, P.R. (5), 1883-1885 and undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
      See also: box 20, folder 378
    - Andrews, Caro Lovejoy (and John) (6), 1880-1896 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - B (24), 1854-1906 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Bingham, Millicent Todd
      See: M.T. Bingham Collection Correspondence
    - Brown, A.B. (3), 1870's (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Buffum, Charles (16), 1892-1907 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - C (12), 1879-1895 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Clark, Sarah D. (5), 1865-1876 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Corwine, Dessie (Mrs. Walter E. Wallis) (42), 1898-1909 and undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Cutter, H. Maria; ________, Marshall M.; ________,? (N.W.?) (13), Circa 1870-1883; 1893, and undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - D (10), 1883-1907 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Darling, Adella Letchworth (3), 1893-1903 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Darrell, Isabel (4), 1903-1905 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Eastman, Mary J. (2), 1887 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - F (5), 1853-1901 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Findley, Maud Kinsley (5), 1900-1904 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Garrison, Mr. and Mrs. Francis J. (Theresa H.) (12), 1903-1908 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Gerry, Mary S. (2), 1893 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Guion, Mary L. (2), 1873 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - H (13), 1878-c. 1906 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Hanna, Robert and Nettie (2), 1903 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Haskell, Florence E. (9), 1903-1909 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Haynes, Fred and Louise (2), 1903 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Hollis, Sarah A. (11), 1866-1905 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Howland, Isabel (3), 1905-1906 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Hyde, Prudence M. (2), 1903 (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - J (5), 1853-1903 (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Jones, Maria B. (Mrs. William) (29), 1857-1874) (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - K (1), 1906 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Kent, Mary C. Wilder (4), 1903 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - King, Isabella L. (Mrs. Horatio) (4), 1884-1886 (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Kittredge, Helen M. (4), 1892-1898 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - L (6), 1893, 1903-1909 and undated (Box 23, Folder 33)
    - Lincoln, Anna (3), 1892-1893 (Box 23, Folder 34)
    - Loomis, E.J. (husband) (53), 1855-1865 (Box 23, Folder 35)
    - ________________ (43), 1866-1867 (Box 23, Folder 36)
    - ________________ (27), 1868-1872 (Box 23, Folder 37)
    - ________________ (34), 1873-1875 (Box 23, Folder 38)
    - ________________ (36), 1876-1878 (Box 23, Folder 39)
    - ________________ (21), 1879-1884 (Box 23, Folder 40)
    - Loomis, E.J. (husband) (30), 1885 (Box 23, Folder 41)
    - ________________ (42), 1886-1887 (Box 23, Folder 42)
    - ________________ (18), 1888 (Box 23, Folder 43)
    - ________________ (including Angola expedition) (15), 1889-1890 (Box 23, Folder 44)
    - ________________ (29), [1891-] 1892 (Box 23, Folder 45)
    - ________________ (9), 1893 (Box 23, Folder 46)
    - M (7), 1879-c. 1904 (Box 24, Folder 47)
    - Marriot, Canon Henry (24), 1903-1908 (Box 24, Folder 48)
    - Mason, Clara and F. Evalyn (cousin—see Jones' genealogy) (5), 1889-1905 (Box 24, Folder 49)
    - McGowan, Josephine P. (3), 1902-1904 (Box 24, Folder 50)
    - Milinowski, Marta (10), 1905-1910 (Box 24, Folder 51)
    - Monnier, M. (3), 1902-1903 (Box 24, Folder 52)
    - Munroe, Mary (11), 1806-1892 (Box 24, Folder 53)
    - N - O (3), 1882-1903 (Box 24, Folder 54)
    - P (5), 1880-1907 (Box 24, Folder 55)
    - Paddon, Ellen (16), 1856-1865 (Box 24, Folder 56)
    - Patterson, Jane A. (11), 1903-1908 (Box 24, Folder 57)
    - Peale, Emilie W. (3), 1888-1903 (Box 24, Folder 58)
    - R (8), 1888-1904 (Box 24, Folder 59)
    - Roberts, J. I. (4), 1903 (Box 24, Folder 60)
    - S (19), 1883-1903 and undated (Box 24, Folder 61)
    - San[d]ford, Elliot; ________, John (3), 1896 (Box 24, Folder 62)
    - Sawyer, Elizabeth C. (33), 1901-1903 (Box 24, Folder 63)
    - ________________ (36), 1904-1910 (Box 24, Folder 64)
    - Shaw, Louisa Jones; ________, Josepha; ________, Amy (10), 1863-1903 (Box 24, Folder 65)
    - Snell, Sabra C. (2), 1903 (Box 24, Folder 66)
    - Stearns, Ednah M. (3), 1887-1895 (Box 24, Folder 67)
    - Stevens, Susan (2), 1871-1875 (Box 24, Folder 68)
    - T (6), 1880's-1900 (Box 24, Folder 69)
    - Talbot, Suzie N. (5), 1881-1886 (Box 24, Folder 70)
    - Thoreau, Sophia (8), 1857-1871, undated (Box 24, Folder 71)
    - Thoreau, Maria (5), 1860-1881 (Box 24, Folder 71)
    - Twiss, Stephen P. (19), 1864-1875 (Box 24, Folder 72)
    - Van Vleck, J.M. (1), 1903 (Box 24, Folder 73)
    - W (16), 1879-1907 and undated (Box 24, Folder 74)
    - Ward, C. Triffit (2), 1900, 1902 (Box 24, Folder 75)
    - Waters, Sarah J. (13), 1892-1900 (Box 24, Folder 76)
    - Wilder, Mr. and Mrs. Charles T.(Mary E. Ware), cousin (2), 1867-1889 (Box 25, Folder 77)
    - Wilder, Esther F. (17), 1871-1918 (Box 25, Folder 78)
    - Wilder, Geo: G.(uncle) (6), 1853-1859 (Box 25, Folder 79)
    - Wilder, Mr. and Mrs. Herbert A. (cousins) (Sara) (21), 1871-1911 (Box 25, Folder 80)
    - Wilder, John A. (brother) (19), 1858-1868 (Box 25, Folder 81)
    - Wilder, M.W.F.S. (mother) (57), 1858-1879 (Box 25, Folder 82)
    - ________________ (32), 1880-1893 (Box 25, Folder 83)
    - Wilder, Richard E. and family (uncle) (da Fanny) (11), 1880-1895 (Box 25, Folder 84)
    - Wilder, Sarah Elizabeth (cousin) (da Jonas) (6), 1892-1903 (Box 25, Folder 85)
    - Williams, Mary E. (9), 1891-1894 (Box 25, Folder 86)
    - unidentified (6), undated (Box 25, Folder 87)
    - M.W.L. draft letters (2), undated (Box 25, Folder 88)
- WILDER FAMILY: GENERAL, 1790-1893 (-1968); Series IV; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series contains the correspondence, legal and financial papers, writings, and miscellany of the Wilder family over three generations, ending in 1893, together with some biographical and genealogical materials dated as late as 1968. The papers of John Augustus Wilder are extensive, and have been assigned a separate series (Series V). The papers of Mary Alden Wilder Loomis (Mrs. Eben J. Loomis) are in Series I and II. This series is divided into two subseries:
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically under the name of the family member to whom the letter is written, then alphabetically by the sender's last name. See the general note on correspondence in the Introduction to the register.
  Personal and Legal Records
  Personal and legal records is preceded by several folders of biographical and genealogical material about the Wilder family, followed by the papers of three members of the Wilder family:
  Rev. John Wilder
  Rev. John Wilder, II
  Mary Wales Fobes Jones Wilder (Mrs. John, II)
  The material for each of these individuals is arranged roughly chronologically.
  - Correspondence
    - Mason, Mr. and Mrs. Wm. A. (Clara) (6)
      - Shaw, Louisa Jones; Wilder, M.W.F. Jones; Jones, Maria B. (6), 1868-1889 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - Todd, David and Todd, Mabel
        See: David Todd and Mabel Todd Collections—Correspondence See: Mabel Todd Juvenilia-Correspondence
    - Shaw, Louisa Jones
      - Wilder, M.W.F. Jones (6), 1840-1842 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Wilder, Charles Baker
      - Wilder, Fannie Everett; ____, Rev. John, 2nd, (2), 1843, 1879 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Official Correspondence - Civil War
        See: box 35 See: box 31, folder 50
    - Wilder, Charles T.
      - Loomis, M.A.W.; Wilder, M.W.F.J. (4), 1879-1883 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Wilder, George Griffin
      - Loomis, Eben J. (1), 1888 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Wilder, Herbert A. Family
      - Fairbank, John Wilder (1), 1899 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - Loomis, Eben J.; Wilder, M.W.F.J. (3), 1882, 1888, and undated (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Todd, David P. and Mabel L.
        See: David P. Todd and Mabel L. Todd Collections, Correspondence
    - Wilder, Rev. John, 2nd
      - Wilder, Mary W.F. Jones (Mrs. John - wife) (2), 1839 and undated (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence re end of ministry, Concord, Mass., 1839
        See: box 28, folder 55
    - Wilder, M.W.F. Jones
      - A-Z (28), 1844-1893 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - Cutter, H.W.; ________, H. Maria; ________, J.M.; ________, Rev. Marshall; ________, Nellie T. (42), 1874-1890 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Jones, Emeline (7), 1859-1889 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - Jones, Maria B. (Mrs. William) (5), 1862-1873 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - Kittredge, Helen (11), 1892-1893 and undated (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - Leavitt, John H. (11), 1862-1866 (Box 26, Folder 14)
      - Loomis, Eben J. (3), 1882-1885 (Box 26, Folder 15)
      - Loomis, Mary A. Wilder (32), 1860-1889 (Box 26, Folder 16)
      - Lowell, Mrs. Charles (2), 1876 (Box 26, Folder 17)
      - Mason, Clara M. (Mrs. Wm.) (5), 1888-1889 (Box 26, Folder 18)
      - Mason, Nellie E. (12), 1880-1892 (Box 26, Folder 19)
      - Palmer, Frederic N., M.D. (8), 1878-1882 and undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
      - Shaw, Joseph Alden; ________, Louise Jones (32), 1858-1891 (Box 26, Folder 21)
      - Smith, Mrs. E. (5), 1886-1887 (Box 26, Folder 22)
      - Smith, Rev. and Mrs. John W. (Amy Ann Wilder) (2), 1846-1847 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Stevens, Flora E.; ________, M.L.; ________, Susie (5), 1871-1902 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Thoreau, Maria (14), 1841-1881 (Box 26, Folder 25)
      - Thoreau, Sophia (3), undated (Box 26, Folder 26)
      - Todd, David P. and Todd, Mabel L.
        See: David P. Todd and Mabel L. Todd Collection, Correspondence
      - Twiss, Stephen (2), 1873-1877 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - W (1), 1892 (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - Wheeler, Harriet L. (4), Circa 1860's-1887 (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - Wilder, Charles Baker; ________, Charles T. (5), 1880-1886 (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Wilder, Esther (6), 1881-1889 (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Wilder, George G. (4), 1844-1881 (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - Wilder, Herbert A. (8), 1870-1893 (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - Wilder, Rev. John, 2nd (1), 1839 (Box 27, Folder 34)
      - Wilder, John A. (61), 1859-1866 (Box 27, Folder 35)
      - Wilder, John A. (20), 1867-1870 (Box 27, Folder 36)
      - Wilder, Richard Everett (13), 1858-1887 (Box 27, Folder 37)
      - Wood, L.A. (4), 1892-1893 (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Wilder, Richard Everett
      - Loomis, M.A.W.; Wilder, John A. (2), 1864, 1884 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Unidentified (4), 1855, 1918 and undated (Box 27, Folder 40)
  - Personal and Legal Records
    - Wilder Genealogy: notes, includes much material on earlier period, Circa 1880-1968 (Box 28, Folder 41)
    - Wilder Family, various bio-graphical and other printed matter; Indian deeds, 1796 [1838], 1798, 1831, 1880-1910, 1938, 1958 (Box 28, Folder 42)
    - Mason Family (sister of Mary W.F. Jones Wilder), various printed matter, 1882-1918 (Box 28, Folder 43)
    - Rev. John Wilder I
      - Biographical information, undated (Box 28, Folder 44)
      - "Discourse at the Ordination of the Rev. John Wilder…Attleborough … 1790," (Box 28, Folder 45)
      - Sermon preached 1798 at Attleborough "On the Federal Fast," (Box 28, Folder 46)
      - Papers re Attleborough Church, Mass., 1790, 1894 (Box 28, Folder 47)
      - Legal papers: will, separation agreement with second wife, 1800-1833 (Box 28, Folder 48)
      - Funeral Sermon of Mrs. Wilder, 1811, by Dr. Emmory, Franklin, Mass. (Box 28, Folder 49)
      - Funeral Sermon, Feb. 13, 1836, by Elisha Fisk (Box 28, Folder 50)
    - Rev. John Wilder II
      - Biographical information, 1836, 1904, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 51)
      - Commonplace Book, 1821 (Box 28, Folder 52)
      - Loose papers (notes, poetry) from Commonplace Book, Circa 1820-1840 (Box 28, Folder 52A)
      - Draft constitution of Marshall Michigan, anti-slavery society, Circa 1840 (Box 28, Folder 52B)
      - Commencement oration at Brown University by J. Wilder, 1822 (Box 28, Folder 53)
      - Lectures delivered, 1822-1840 (Box 28, Folder 53A)
      - Sermon preached by J. Wilder at dedication of Calvinist Meeting House, Hardwick, Mass., 1829 (Box 28, Folder 54)
      - Letters and papers re end of ministry, Concord, Mass. in 1839, 1837-1839 (Box 28, Folder 55)
      - Concord (Trinitarian) Congregational Church: histories mentioning his ministry, 1876, 1895 (Box 28, Folder 56)
      - Funeral sermon 1844, gravestone inscription 1901, 1844, 1901 (Box 28, Folder 57)
    - Mary W.F.J. Wilder
      - Financial: pew purchase, 1835-1854 (Box 29, Folder 58)
      - Financial papers: bills, bonds, loan to cutter, 1859-1893 (Box 29, Folder 59)
      - Writings: published in Christian Union, 1886-1889 (Box 29, Folder 60)
      - Writings: "The Birds' Concert" in The Triangle, 1891 (Box 29, Folder 61)
      - Drafts of children's stories, 1893 and undated (Box 29, Folder 62)
      - Various draft writings, undated (Box 29, Folder 63)
      - Miscellaneous writings and, notes of others, undated (Box 29, Folder 64)
      - Miscellaneous printed matter and notes (Box 29, Folder 65)
      - Aug. 23, 1893, death, letters about, to Mrs. E.J. Loomis (Box 29, Folder 66)
      - Will and cemetery lot, 1866, 1893 (Box 29, Folder 67)
      - Obituaries, August 1893 (Box 29, Folder 68)
- JOHN AUGUSTUS WILDER (1836?-1870), 1843-1870, 1909; Series V
  This series contains the correspondence, legal and financial papers, diaries, notebooks, educational papers, and writings of John A. Wilder, together with a number of army papers deriving from Wilder's career as a Union officer in the Civil War. The series is divided into three sub-series:
  Correspondence covers the entire period 1843-1870, and is arranged alphabetically by correspondent. See the general note on correspondence in the Introduction to the register. A few items, particularly those relating to the trial of Major Gee, have been filed under "Civil War Records"; cross-reference to these letters has been made in the register.
  Civil War Records
  Civil War Records covers only the period 1862-1866. It is preceded by printed matter on Wilder's career during those years, and by some non-military material from those years. The rest of this subseries is arranged as follows:
  Wilder's passes and commissions
  Regimental orders, muster rolls, descriptive lists
  Regimental records: Quartermaster, ordnance, company finance
  Photographs, correspondence of others, miscellany
  Wilder's army legal work (including Gee trial)
  Special Files
  Special Files contains the papers of John A. Wilder for the years 1852-1862 and 1867-1870, preceded by some biographical information dated as late as 1909.
  The sub-series is divided by type into:
  Personal, Legal and Financial Documents
  Diaries and Notebooks
  Education
  Professional (Law Practice)
  Miscellaneous
  - Correspondence
    - A-F (20), 1855-1869 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - Allison, Emma (6), 1867-1868 and undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - Ammidon, P.R. (12), 1853-1857 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Andrew, John A. (Gov. of Mass.) (8), 1863-1864 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - Bass, Lyman R. (8), 1854-1858 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Birney, William (2), 1863 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - Bissell, Theodore (1), undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Blake, J. Vila (3), 1863 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Calderwood, W. (3), 1853-1854 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Call, W.
      See: box 32, folder 83
    - Crittenden, Edw. W. (6), 1857-1860 and undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Cunningham, Amanda (22), 1853-1856 and undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Cushing, Levi L. (3), 1860-1861 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Cutter, James M.; ________, Samuel L., Jr. (2), 1862-1870 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Denman, Edward S. (7), 1853-1855 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Fellows, Col. Stark (and Rufus, his father) (3), 1863-1866 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - Fuller, Wm. J. A. (6), 1865-1867 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - G-P (29), 1853-1872 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Gee, Charles A., and Gee, John
    - Grovestine, Nettie (5), 1856 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - Gunn, W.A.
    - Hallowell, N.P.; ________, R.P. (6), 1863 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Henshaw, William O. (3), 1853 and undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Hickok, L.P. (3), 1853-1856 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - Holland, P.P. and Mary E. (6), 1865-1867 and undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Holmes, Dr. Oliver Wendell (3), 1865-1866 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Holt, Joseph (Judge Advocate Gen.) (3), 1864-1865 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Hughes, Judge (4)
    - Leavitt, John H. (4), 1859-1862 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Loomis, Eben J. (11), 1855-1869 (Box 30, Folder 26)
      See also: box 30, folder 42
    - Loomis, Mahlon (3), 1853-1857 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Loomis, Mary Alden Wilder (11), 1853-1869 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Mundee, Charles (1), 1866 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Newton, Gen. John (1), 1865 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Oliver, J.E. (2), 1853 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Pierce, Edward L. (2), 1864-1865 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - R-Z (18), 1852-1866 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Rembough, Alonzo C. (12), 1863-1866 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Schouler, Adj't Gen.
      See: box 30, folder 4
    - Shaw, Joseph Alden (3), 1859-1861, and undated (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Stanton, E.M.
    - Sykes, Charles R. (2), 1863 and undated (Box 30, Folder 36)
      See also: box 30, folder 6
    - Todd, Mabel
      See: Mabel Todd Collection, Correspondence and Juvenilia: Correspondence
    - Twiss, Stephen P. (11), 1853-1860 and undated (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Vaughan, Augustus M., Post Master, Norfolk, Va. (3), 1860 and undated (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - Wilder, Charles B. (8), 1856-1862 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Wilder, George Griffin (10), 1854-1868 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Wilder, Herbert A. (4), 1864-1870 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Wilder, Mary A. (Mrs. Eben J. Loomis)
      See: box 30, folder 28
    - Wilder, Mary W.F. Jones (35), 1853-1869 and undated (Box 30, Folder 42)
      See also: box 30, folder 28
    - Wilder, various (7), 1843-1869 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - Williams, Charles H.S. (5), 1855-1866 (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - Winter, Will (7), 1854-1862 and undated (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Wyman, Charles T. (4), 1856-1858 (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - Yale College; Dartmouth College; Union College (3), 1852 (?)-1853 and undated (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - Friends, unidentified (7), 1854-1862 and undated (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - Letters of introduction for J.A. Wilder (29), 1861-1869 (Box 30, Folder 49)
  - Civil War Records
    - Biographical data re 1862-1866 and background (printed) matter about aspects of J.A. Wilder's career, 1862-1866, 1862-1866, 1929, 1964, and undated (Box 31, Folder 50)
    - Description of related correspondence, undated (Box 31, Folder 51)
    - Small diaries of J.A. Wilder, 1864 (cover only), 1865, 1866, 1864-1866 (Box 31, Folder 52)
    - J.A. Wilder: assorted financial papers, 1863-1866 (Box 31, Folder 53)
    - J.A. Wilder: misc. notes, invitations, etc. from 1862-1866 (Box 31, Folder 54)
    - J.A. Wilder: letters of introduction and passes, April 1862-July 1863, 1862-1863 (Box 31, Folder 55)
    - J.A. Wilder: Personal and troop appointments, assignments, commissions (54th Regt Mass. Colored Volunteers), Jan. 1862-June 1863, 1862-1863 (Box 31, Folder 56)
    - J.A. Wilder: Personal and troop appointments, assignments, commissions (2nd U.S. Colored Infantry Regt), June 1863-Jan 1866, 1863-1866 (Box 31, Folder 57)
    - Organization of contrabands in Virginia area 1862-1865—correspondence of Charles B. Wilder and others, orders from War Dept.
      See: folio 35
    - General orders, special orders, and other documents re organization of colored troops, July 1862-July 1865, 1862-1865 (Box 31, Folder 58)
    - U.S. Army 2nd Regt of Colored Troops
      1) requisitions n.d.
      2) invoices Aug 1864-March 1865
      3) receipts Aug 1864-March 1865
      4) expenditures April 1864-Feb 1865
      - Muster rolls, June-Dec 1863 (Box 31, Folder 59)
      - Descriptive lists, clothing, and pay, June 1863-April 1864 (alphabetical order), 1863-1864 (Box 31, Folder 60)
      - Sick notices from Philadelphia, Ft. Monroe, Va., Pt. Lookout, Md., David's Island, N.Y., July-Sept 1864 (Box 31, Folder 61)
      - Inventories, effects, dead soldiers, Jan-Nov 1864 (Box 31, Folder 62)
      - Correspondence re Quartermaster's reports, and clothing and equipment issue, Aug 1863-Nov 1865, 1863-1865 (Box 31, Folder 63)
      - Clothing and equipment requisitions, June 1863-May 1864, chronological order, 1863-1864 and undated (Box 31, Folder 64)
      - Clothing and equipment; invoices, July 1863-May 1864; receipts, July 1863-June 1864, 1863-1864 (Box 31, Folder 65)
      - Monthly return of clothing and equipment received and issued, July-Aug 1863: chronological order. U.S. Army Form #52; camp and garrison equipage: receipt roll of clothing (Box 31, Folder 66)
      - Clothing and personal equipment issues, June 1863-Dec 1863: chronological order (Box 31, Folder 67)
      - Clothing and personal equipment issues, Jan 1864-June 1864; notes from Jan 1866 and n.d., in chronological order; U.S. Army Form #52, 1864, 1866 (Box 31, Folder 68)
      - Ordnance correspondence, Sept 1864-Dec 1865, 1864-1865 (Box 32, Folder 69)
      - Ordnance:, 1864-1865 (Box 32, Folder 70)
      - Ordnance: quarterly returns, July 1863-March 1865, 1863-1865 (Box 32, Folder 71)
      - Financial records of company savings funds: July 1864-June 1865, 1864-1865 (Box 32, Folder 72)
      - Miscellaneous financial records, Jan 1864-Dec 1865 and n.d., 1864-1865 and undated (Box 32, Folder 73)
    - Photographs of persons and places connected with 2nd U.S. Colored Regt, undated (Box 32, Folder 74)
    - Correspondence of others, mainly re Colored Regt and aid to escaped slaves, 1862-1864 (Box 32, Folder 75)
    - Miscellaneous notes and memos by J.A. Wilder, late 1864-1866, re regimental business (Box 32, Folder 76)
    - Miscellaneous undated lists and notes re regimental supplies and food (Box 32, Folder 77)
    - Army Legal Work
      - J.A. Wilder: activity as member Boards of Survey (stores) re: Feb-Oct 1864, and report of survey on Wilder, Jan 1865, 1864, 1865 (Box 32, Folder 78)
      - J.A. Wilder: activities as judge in court martial and field officer for regimental court, April-Sept 1864, Key West, Fla. (Box 32, Folder 79)
      - J.A. Wilder: activities as presiding judge of Provost Court, Key West, Fla., Nov 1864-May 1865, 1864-1865 (Box 32, Folder 80)
      - J.A. Wilder: activity as Judge Advocate in Military Justice Commissions (Florida), July 1865 - Oct 1865 (Box 32, Folder 81)
      - Trial of Major John H. Gee (Confederate), keeper of Salisbury N.C. Prison Camp; reports from Raleigh, N.C., Jan-April 1866 (Box 32, Folder 82)
      - Trial of Major Gee: papers and letters re defense by J.A. Wilder, Aug 1865 - May 1866, 1865-1866 (Box 32, Folder 83)
      - Printed matter re military law in Civil War, 1862-1865 (Box 32, Folder 84)
  - Special Files
    - Biographical information, obituaries, etc., 1870-1909 (Box 33, Folder 85)
    - Personal, Legal, and Financial Documents
      - Union College: fees and reports, correspondence re same, 1853-1856 (Box 33, Folder 86)
      - Diploma of Adelphi Society, Union College, 1856
      - Cambridge Academy (Harvard Law School), certificates and bill, 1856-1864; Massachusetts Bar admission 1857 (Box 33, Folder 87)
      - Legal papers 1856-1863
        See: box 34, folder 103
      - City of Cambridge taxes, 1859-1862 (Box 33, Folder 88)